Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ nguyenkhoihoang (LinkedIn) github.com/KhoiHoang2410/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Ruby on Rails C (Programming Language) Ruby

Certifications

Efficient One - Shot Video Object Segmentation

Honors-Awards

3rd Price of Vietnam Olympiad of Informatics

2nd Price of National Young Informatics Competition

Nguyen-Khoi Hoang

Software Engineer at Ascenda

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Summary

I am addicted to programming since 15 year olds. I started with competitive programming, gained many prizes in this field. I like the feeling when coding and understand the codebase, let the code run inside my head and try to optimize it. I want to become good backend engineer.

Experience

Ascenda

4 years

Executive Software Engineering March 2023 - Present (2 years 2 months) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Junior Software Engineer

August 2021 - February 2023 (1 year 7 months)

- Maintain / Implement feature for e-commerce website. Try to fasten,
 optimized performance of APIs / background job. Refactor code if needed
- Communicate, planning new feature for campaign
- Mentor new team members

Software Engineer Intern May 2021 - July 2021 (3 months)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Learning new technique: Ruby, Hanami, PostgreSQL, Redis, etc.
- Implement / Maintain / Upgrade APIs of e-commerce website. While catchingup with context of the team, codebase I also doing some task to normalize data of item, expose item data for FE to rendering.
- Implement a feature to merging duplicate item for better rendering.
- I have discover an issue with framework that make API took 8s to process and improve it faster 20x times.

Education

VNUHCM - University of Science
Bachelor's degree, Advanced Program in Computer Science · (2018 - 2022)

Le Quy Don High School for the Gifted - Khanh Hoa High School Diploma · (2015 - 2018)